shopperhive.co.uk 2011-12-27

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

We (Shopperhive) take the privacy rights of users of the Website (www.shopperhive.co.uk) very seriously and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

This Privacy Policy is incorporated in and subject to the Terms & Conditions. By using the Website, you agree to the use of your Personal Information (as defined below) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this use, please do not use the Website or any of the services offered on the Website.

## Who are we?

Any Personal Information you provide to us is held by Shopperhive Ltd, a company registered in the UK with the company number 6889894.

## Personal Information

"Personal Information" means any information about you which is personally identifiable which may include (but might not be limited to) your name, age, gender, address, telephone number, email address, financial details and any other information from which you can be identified and which you may disclose to us or otherwise via the Website at any time. 

## When do we collect your Personal Information?

We may collect and process Personal Information when: 

  1. You provide Account Information when you register and sign up for a User Account, when you subscribe to our Monthly Newsletter or when you enter into any competition, promotion, prize draw or survey on the Website;
  2. You view or buy a product or service from a merchant listing its offers on our Website;
  3. You make a complaint or enquiry or provide feedback to us; or
  4. You disclose Personal Information to us or through the Website at any point.

We will indicate where the provision of Personal Information is optional. If you choose not to provide such Personal Information you may find that some services or use of features of the Website are unavailable to you. 

## How do we use your Personal Information?

We may use your Personal Information in the following ways:

  1. To process the registration and maintain the use of your User Account;
  2. To allow you to participate in certain services such as the Monthly Newsletter, self generated Reviews or any competition, promotion, prize draw or survey on the Website or to inform you of changes to any of these services;
  3. To help us understand what products you have viewed or purchased through the Website in order to provide a better and more personalised service to you including advising of and offering products, services, content and special offers;
  4. To analyse use of the Website including user demographics, interest and behaviour to optimise the services we offer;
  5. To investigate any suspected breach of the Terms & Conditions by or relating to you;

## Do we share your Personal Information with third parties?

We may pass on your Personal Information to other parties as follows:

  1. To select and trusted third parties who may use your Personal Information to serve you content that may be of interest to you. These third parties are not permitted to share or sell your information to anyone else;
  2. To business partners to process the registration and maintain the use of your membership account or subscription and to assist us in providing services to you. Such business partners are required to maintain the confidentiality of Personal Information and, unless you are otherwise advised, do not have any rights to use Personal Information that we provide to them for any purpose beyond what is necessary to assist us;
  3. Some aggregated information about the Website users, sales patterns, traffic volumes and related matters to reputable third parties but these details will not include any information personally identifying you;
  4. To the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisers in connection with any alleged criminal offence or suspected breach of the Terms & Conditions or where required by law;
  5. To any member within Shopperhive Ltd; and
  6. In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose Personal Information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

## How do you edit and delete your User Account or Newsletter subscription information and preferences?

You can edit your Newsletter account information and preferences at any time, including whether you want Shopperhive to contact you about products, services, content and special offers. If you do not wish to receive the Monthly Newsletter then you can also click on the link to unsubscribe, contained at the bottom of the Monthly Newsletter email or contact our customer services department. 

## How long do we hold Personal Information for?

We only hold Personal Information for as long as is necessary for the purposes described above in the paragraph headed "How do we use Personal Information?" 

## How do we protect Personal Information?

We employ all industry standard practices and have strict security procedures covering the collection, storage and disclosure of Personal Information in order to prevent unauthorised access and to comply with relevant UK data protection laws. All Personal Information you provide to us is stored on our or our business partners' secure servers. The secure servers encrypt all Personal Information you input before it is sent to us. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask that you do not to share your password with anyone. 

## What are cookies and how do we use them?

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. 

Cookies help us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us to: 

  1. estimate our audience size and usage pattern;
  2. store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our Website according to your individual interests;
  3. speed up your searches;
  4. recognise you when you return to our Website.

In addition to our cookies, we allow certain third parties and affiliates to set and access cookies on your computer. Some of these third parties may collect and use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to serve you content that might be of interest to you. These third parties' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies and not Shopperhive's. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our Website. 

To see what cookies are beeing used by Shopperhive please refer to the tabel below.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | More information  
---|---|---|---  
Essential site cookie | shukid | This cookie is essential for the user account to operate and is set upon your arrival to the logon parts of the Shopperhive site. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser. |    
View Type site cookie | v | This cookie is used to store your search results view type preferences such as grid or list. |    
Stored Wishilits site cookie | wl | This cookie is used to remeber your wishlists when created as an anonymous user. |    
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz |  We use Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  | [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
Clicky | cluid  
_jsuid |  We use Clicky Web Analytics to monitor, analyze, and react to visitor traffic in real time. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form.  | [Click here for the Clicky terms](http://getclicky.com/#/terms)  
Google AdSense | * |  Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Shopperhive's users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet.  | Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).  
  
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

## Where do we store Personal Information?

We hold Personal Information on virtual servers and servers in the UK. Our virtual servers are operated by a third party in the USA. US laws on holding Personal Information are less stringent than the laws applicable in the UK, but we will hold and transmit your Personal Information in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable UK data protection laws.

## Access to information

You have the right to access information held about you. If you would like to receive a copy of your Personal Information held by us, please contact us here. 

We may charge you a small administrative fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of your Personal Information which we hold. 

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the 14th Aug 2011.

## Posting Personal Information on publicly accessible areas

A publicly accessible area of the Website is any area that is accessible by the general public and may be indexed by search engines. You are solely responsible for any Personal Information that you disclose and disseminate on publicly accessible areas. You should never disclose Personal Information relating to any other person without their express consent. 

## Other Links

Our Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any of your Personal Information to these websites. 

## Want to know more?

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy or how we use your Personal Information, please contact our legal department here. 

End of Privacy Policy  
\--------------------------
